<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data sovereignty on Te Rourou Tātaritanga</title>
    <link>https://terourou.org/tags/data-sovereignty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data sovereignty on Te Rourou Tātaritanga</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 14:55:33 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://terourou.org/tags/data-sovereignty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>iNZight: A GUI for Data Visualisation and Analysis through R</title>
      <link>https://terourou.org/outputs/inzight-jss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 14:55:33 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terourou.org/outputs/inzight-jss/</guid>
      <description>Visualisation, exploration, and analysis of data is often inaccessible to many due to high up-front costs of learning the necessary coding skills to get started. Graphical user interfaces (GUIs) have often been used to provide inexperienced users with access to these underlying, complex systems without the need for coding. R GUIs are available, but they require some degree of experience with R and a familiarity with statistical concepts. iNZight is a GUI-based tool written in R that enables both students and researchers to interact with and explore data without the need for code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iNZight 4.1: Big updates for survey handling</title>
      <link>https://terourou.org/outputs/inzight_4.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 14:55:33 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terourou.org/outputs/inzight_4.1/</guid>
      <description>The latest release features a major overhaul of iNZight&amp;rsquo;s handling of survey designs, as well as several other significant user interface changes. Our focus has been on making iNZight a development tool for researchers to use on a wide range of data, specifically from survey designs, in a way that minimises specialist skills (such as understanding the underlying structure of the survey).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
